projectmanager.com 2019-12-11

# Privacy Policy - ProjectManager.com

## What this policy covers

[ProjectManager.com](https://www.projectmanager.com/), Ltd (ProjectManager) is committed to protecting the privacy of the personal information of individuals and companies we deal with.

This privacy policy is intended to help you understand:

  * What information we collect about you
  * How we use information we collect
  * How we share information we collect
  * How we store and secure information we collect
  * How to access and control your information
  * How we transfer information we collect internationally
  * Other important privacy information

When we refer to “ProjectManager,” “we,” or “us” in this policy, we mean ProjectManager.com, Inc., which controls the information ProjectManager collects when you use our Products. ProjectManager offers project management and collaboration tools, including our web, desktop and mobile products, which help you plan your work and communicate with your teams. We also own and operate a number of websites and offer related services, such as customer support. We refer to all of these websites, services, apps and platforms as “Products” in this policy.

This Privacy Policy governs our data collection, processing and usage practices and describes your options regarding use, access and the ability to correct your personal information. By using the Website or the Subscription Service, you are consenting to the data practices detailed in this Privacy Policy. **If you disagree with the data practices detailed in this Privacy Policy.**

## What information we collect about you

We collect information about you when you provide it to us, when you use our Products, and when other sources provide it to us, as described below.

### Information you provide to us

We collect information about you that you input or upload to our Products or otherwise provide directly to us.

 **Account and Profile Information.** We collect information about you when you sign up for an account, create or modify your profile information, set account preferences, and make purchases through our Products. For example, you provide your contact information and, in many cases, billing information when you sign up for our Products. You also have the option of adding a profile photo, and other contact details to your profile information to be displayed in our Products. We keep track of your preferences when you select these and other settings within our Products.

 **Content that you provide through our Products.** We collect and store content that you post, send, receive and share via our Products. This content includes any information about you that you may choose to include. Content also includes any files and links you choose to upload to our Products. For example, the types of content we collect and store might include: files you attach to tasks, the name of a task list, board, team or project; descriptions of tasks; comments you add to tasks; image uploads; or profile photo uploads.

 **Content you provide through our websites.** As indicated above, our Products also include websites owned or operated by us. We collect content that you choose to submit to these websites, including social media and networking websites operated by us. For example, you provide content to us when you provide feedback or when you participate in any interactive features such as request forms, surveys, contests, promotions, sweepstakes, activities or events.

 **Information you provide via our customer support portal.** Our Products also include customer support, where you may choose to submit information regarding a question you have or issue you are experiencing with our Products. When you submit a contact form, open a support ticket, speak to one of our representatives directly or otherwise engage with our support team, you may choose to provide contact information, a description of your issue, or any documentation, images or information that might be helpful in resolving your issue.

 **Payment Information:** We collect certain payment and billing information when you sign up and or subscribe to certain paid Products, such as credit card numbers, billing details, bank information and related personal information necessary to process payments as required by law. We use third party PCI-compliant service providers to process your billing transactions securely and to implement anti-fraud protection measures.

### Information we collect automatically when you use our Products

We collect information about you when you use our Products, including browsing our websites or using and taking certain actions within our Products.

 **Your use of our Products:** We keep track of certain information about you when you visit and interact with any of our Products. This information may include the features you use; the type, size and filenames of attachments you upload to our Products; frequently used search terms; and volume of support inquiries.

 **Device and Connection Information:** When you visit our Products, we may automatically collect navigational information about your browser or equipment, as well as browsing actions and usage patterns, including:

  * Information about your internet connection and computer, including IP address, operating system and browser type. We may use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your location to provide you with a better experience across our Products.
  * Details of your visits to our Products, including service usage data, internet traffic data, location data and other navigational data.

The type and amount of this information we collect may depend on the type and settings of the device you use to access our Products.

 **Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:** Technologies we use for this automatic navigational data collection may include:

  * Cookies. Your browser may have settings enabling you to refuse to accept cookies. Our Products will issue cookies when you visit them, unless you have adjusted your own browser settings. We cannot guarantee our Products will be fully accessible if you adjust your browser setting to refuse cookies.
  * Flash Cookies. Some areas of our Products may use locally stored objects (or Flash cookies) to collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from and on our Products.
  * Web Beacons. Several areas of our Products, including our 3rd party email providers, may use web beacons (aka clear gifs. pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that enable us to track or count users to measure performance).

## Information we receive from other sources

We receive information about you from other users of our Products, from 3rd party Products, and from our business and channel partners.

 **Other users of our Products:** Other users of our Products may provide information about you when they submit content through our Products. For example, we receive your email address from other users when they choose to invite you to our Products. Similarly, your contact info might be added by a system administrator, or a team member may upload content about you to a list or project.

 **Other Products you link to your account:** When you or your administrator enable third-party apps or integrations, your information might be added or shared. For example, if you create an account or log into our Products using Google Apps marketplace, we receive your name and email address as permitted by your Google profile settings in order to authenticate you. Or you may authorize our Products to sync a Google calendar. Or, you or your administrator might integrate our Products with 3rd party Products, such as Zapier, which may allow you to access, store, share and edit information from a third-party through our Products. The information we receive or transmit when you link or integrate our Products with a third-party service depends on the settings, permissions and privacy policy controlled by you and that third-party service. It is recommended that you check the privacy policies and notices in any third-party Products you authoritze to understand what data may be disclosed to us or shared via our Products.

 **ProjectManager’s Partners:** We may work with third-party partners or vendors who provide consulting, training or other services around our Products. Some of these partners help us to promote and market our Products and/or resell our Products. Some might be advertising and market research partners who provide us with information about your interest in or engagement with our Products and online advertisements. We may receive information from these partners, such as contact and location data, company name, products you have purchased or may be interested in and any evaluation information you have provided.

## How we use information we collect

We collect different information depending on which Products you use, how you choose to use them, and any preferences you have communicated to us about how that information is used. Here are specific purposes in which we use information we collect about you:

 **To deliver our Products to you:** We use information we collect about you in order to provide our Products to you. This may include using your email address to authenticate you when you sign up and/or log in, to process billing transactions for your account, to deliver customer success, and to operate and maintain our Products. For example within our platform, we use the name and picture you might provide to identify you to other users of the platform. We may also use your email domain to infer your affiliation with a particular organization or industry to personalize the content and experience on our websites.

 **For customer support:** We will use your information to resolve product assistance requests, to analyze and address technical issues you encounter, and to repair and optimize our Products for you.

 **For service improvement, research and development:** We always strive to improve our Products and find new ways to make them better for you. We use generalized data to understand how people use our Products, as well as feedback communicated directly to us. This might be in order to identify trends, usage patterns, to troubleshoot issues, and to make improvement of our Products. We also test and evaluate Service speed and performance regularly to maintain optimum deliverability, as well as test and analyze new features or Products with some users in beta before delivering product changes to all users.

 **To communicate with you about our Products:** In order to deliver our Products to you, we use your contact information in order to send transactional communications via email and within our Products. This may include in order to confirm a subscription purchase or change, to alert you when a subscription is expiring or being canceled, in order to provide customer support, and to communicate with you about technical updates, product releases, administrative messages or security alerts. Depending on your alert or role and user settings, we send you email notifications when you or others interact on our Products, for example, when you are shared on a project or task, or if you are communicating with others on a discussion thread. We also send you Products communications to help you onboard and engage with a particular Service in order to help you become more proficient in using that Service. These communications are part of our Products and in most cases you cannot opt out of them. When an opt out is available, you will find that option (such as an unsubscribe link) within the communication itself or via your account or alerts settings.

 **To market, promote, and drive engagement with our Products:** We use your contact information and data related to how you use our Products to send promotional communications that may be of specific interest to you, including by email and by displaying ProjectManager ads on other websites, platforms and applications, such as Facebook and Google. These communication mechanisms are used to promote engagement and to help you get the most out of our Products, and they may include news about new features, requests for reviews or feedback, survey requests, and informational email newsletters. We may also communicate with you about product promotions, offers and contests. You can decide whether you want to receive these communications as described below under “Opt-out of communications.”

 **For safety and security:** As part of our security protocols, we use information about you and your Products in several different ways. We use information in order to verify your activity and transactions, to identify any violations of our Products terms of use, and to monitor suspicious or fraudulent activity.

 **To protect our legitimate business interests and legal rights:** Where it is required by law or where we believe it is necessary to protect our legal rights, interests and the interests of others, we use information about you in connection with legal claims, regulatory and audit functions, compliance, and required disclosures related to the sale, acquisition, or merger of a business.

 **With your consent:** For specific purposes not already listed above, we use information about you when you have given us explicit consent. For example, with your permission, we may publish customer reviews or testimonial videos in order to promote our Products on our websites.

 **Legal bases for processing (for EEA users):** For individuals located in the European Economic Area (EEA), we collect and process information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws, and depending on our Products you use, as well as how you use them. Therefore we only collect and use your information:

  * In order to deliver to you our Products, including operating our Products, providing customer support, and to protect the security of our Products;
  * In order to satisfy a legitimate interest (which is not overridden by your data protection interests), such as to protect our legal rights and interests, or for research and development, or to promote and market our Products;
  * When we need to process your information in order to comply with legal obligations; or
  * When you give us consent to do so for specific purposes.

Where we use your information because we or a third party (such as your employer) have a legitimate interest in order to do so, you have the right to object to such use, however this may mean no longer using our Products. When and if you consent to our use of your information for a specific purpose, you have the right to change your mind at any time, however, this will not impact any processing that has already occurred.

We make project management and collaboration tools. We are not in the business of selling your information to advertisers or other third parties. In order to deliver the best Products to you, we may share information through our Products with certain third parties in the following ways.

### Sharing with other users

As part of our offering, we share certain information about you with other users.

 **For collaboration:** In our Products, you can create content in which you might choose to include information about yourself, as well as enable others to see, edit, share, collaborate copy and download, based on settings you or your account administrators have selected. Some of the features of our Products may also display all or some of your profile information to other users. For example, when you join an account, project or a team, your contact information may be displayed in a contact list for other team members so they can find and interact with you. Or when you comment on a task, other users can see your profile picture (if you choose to upload on) and name next to your comments so that other users with access to the card understand who made the comment. Additionally, some of the features enable sharing with other team members or even with people outside of the account. You can check the account or feature permission settings at any time to confirm whether a particular feature is shared or private.

 **Community Sites:** Our websites and social media or social networking sites such as LinkedIn Groups or Twitter, may offer publicly accessible blogs, community threads and forums. We do not have control over any information or content that is posted on those sites, and we refer you to their privacy policies. To request removal of your information from a publicly accessible website that is operated by us, please contact us via the information provided below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your information, in which case we will let you know if that is the case and why.

## Sharing with third parties

We share information with third parties in order to help us operate, deliver, integrate, improve, augment, customize, support and market our Products to you.

 **Service Providers:** In order to provide application and website development, hosting, virtual infrastructure, maintenance, backup, storage, payment processing, analytics and other related products and services we work with third party service providers that may require access or use of your information. Third party service providers must receive instruction from us to access your data and abide by the policies and procedures that are designed to protect your information.

 **ProjectManager Partners:** We may share your information with third parties we employ to provide technical, sales, support and consulting Products in order to implement and deliver customer solutions for our Products. Examples of how your information might be shared include Products that support billing and collections, product customizations and support functions.

 **Third-Party apps:** When you enable or integrate via Third Party Apps, you or your account administrator or even other Service users may give those apps access to your information, including your contact information, account information and any content you transmit or share via those apps. We do not control third-party app policies and procedures, and this privacy policy does not cover how third-party apps use your information. It is recommended that you review the privacy policies of third parties prior to enabling or using them in conjunction with our Products. If you have an objection as to how your information is being shared with these third parties, please disable or discontinue use of the app.

 **Links to Third-Party Sites:** Your use of and any information you submit to any of third-party sites that might be linked to from our Products is governed by their privacy policies, not this one.

 **Third-Party Widgets:** Your interactions with certain widgets, browser extensions or social media features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it, though they may be hosted by the third party or directly on our Products. An example is a “Like” on Facebook button which may collect your IP address or set cookies.

 **With your consent:** When you give us written consent to do so, we share information about you with third parties. An example might be to display written testimonials of customers on our website, which may include your name alongside the testimonial.

 **Compliance with Enforcement Requests and Applicable Laws; Enforcement of Our Rights:** In rare circumstances, we may share information about you with a third party if we believe it is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request, including to meet national security requirements, (b) protect the security or integrity of our Products, ( c ) enforce our policies, agreements and terms of service, (d) protect ProjectManager, our customers or the public from harm or illegal activities, or (e) respond to an emergency which we believe in good faith requires us to disclose information to assist in preventing the death or serious bodily injury of any person.

## Sharing with affiliated companies

Affiliated companies are those companies that are owned and/or operated by ProjectManager.com, Inc. We share information we have about you with ProjectManager affiliated companies to operate and deliver our Products to you. We may also share information with prospective affiliate companies. This privacy policy applies to any information we may share in that circumstance.

In the event of a business transfer, such as a merger, sale of company assets, financing, or the acquisition of all or a portion of the ProjectManager businesses to another company, we may share or transfer information we collect under this privacy policy. If such a transaction takes place, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Products, and such commuincations will include any choices you may have regarding your information.

## How we store and secure information we collect

### Information storage and security

We use data hosting service providers in the United States to host the information we collect. We also use technical measures to secure your data and implement safety measures designed to protect your information. However, due to the inherent nature of the Internet, and given that no security system is impenetrable, we cannot guarantee that data while stored on our systems, during transmission through the Internet or otherwise in our care, is absolutely safe from outside intrusion. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe.

### How long we keep information

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information, as described in further detail below.

 **Account information:** We retain your account information until 90 days after you cancel your account, in order to assist customers with retrieving data after cancellation requests, which we process within 24 hours. After 90 days, your data is deleted from our servers. We retain some of your account information as required to comply with our legal obligations, to support business operations, to enforce agreements, to resolve disputes, and to continue to improve our Products. Where we retain information for Service improvement and product development, we take steps to anonymize information, and we only use such information to uncover collective usage patterns and data insights about the use of our Products.

 **Information you share on our Products:** If your user login is deactivated or disabled, some of your information and the content you have provided on our Products will remain in order to allow other account users to make full use of our Products even when you have left. For example, we continue to display comments and content you provided to task discussions or on projects to retain operational integrity to those remaining on the account.

 **Marketing information:** We retain information delivered from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time from the date that information was created. If you elect to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences unless you specifically ask us to delete such information.

## How to access and control your information

You have certain choices available to you when it comes to your information. Below is a summary of those choices, how to exercise them and any limitations. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe.

### Your Choices:

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including for marketing purposes), to request the deletion or restriction of your information, or to request your information in a structured, electronic format. Below, we describe the tools and processes for making these requests. In many situations, you can exercise some of your choices by logging into our Products and managing your account settings. If some or all of your Products are administered for you by an administrator (see “Notice to End Users” below), you should contact your administrator to facilitate your requests. For all other requests and inquiries, you may contact us as provided in the Contact Us section below.

 **Your request and choices may be limited in certain cases:** Some limitations for requests may be limited, for example, if fulfilling your request would require revealing information about another person. Another example is if you request to delete information that we or your account administrator have compelling legitimate interests to keep or are permitted by law to have. In instances where you have asked us to share data with third parties, for example, by enabling an integration, you will need to direct your requests to those third-party service providers directly.

 **Access and update your information:** Our Products enable you to access and update certain information about you. As an example, from within the Service, you can access and update your profile information within your account settings including modifying content that contains information about you through the use the editing tools associated with that setting.

 **Remove access to a project, team or account:** You or an administrator can remove your access to a project, team, list, board or account. If you can remove your own access, that setting is available to you in the project or list or board settings. If you don’t have access or don’t know how to accomplish removal, please contact your administrator or ProjectManager support. Be aware that removing access to a project, team or account does not delete your information; your information remains visible to other Service users based on your past participation within our Products. For more information on how to delete your information, see below.

 **Delete your information:** Our Products enable you to delete certain information about you from within the Service. For example, you can remove content that contains information via the editing tools associated with that content or feature, if you have appropriate access, and you can remove certain profile information within your profile settings. You may need to contact your account administrator to accomplish this for you. As indicated, we may need to retain information for certain record keeping purposes, or to complete or authorize transactions, or to comply with our legal obligations.

 **Request that we stop using your information:** In certain cases, you may request that we stop storing, accessing, using or otherwise processing your information where you believe we haven’t obtained the appropriate rights to do so. As an example, if you believe an account to the Service was created without your permission or you are no longer an active user, you can request that we delete your account as noted in this policy. In instances where you provided us with consent to use your information for a limited purpose, you can contact us to withdraw your consent, but this will not impact any processing that has already taken place prior to the withdrawal of consent. As indicated previously, if you have objections to information about how your information is being shared with a third-party app, please disable or discontinue use of the app or contact your administrator to facilitate the request on your behalf.You also are able to opt-out of our use of your information for marketing purposes by contacting us with the information provided below. When you make any change of consent or information accessibility requests, we may require time to investigate and facilitate such requests. Any delays or disputes regarding our right to continue using your information, providing your account administrator does not object, will initiate a restriction of further use of your information until dispute is resolved or request is honored.

 **Opt out of communications:** You may choose to opt out of receiving promotional communications from us by updating your email alerts settings within your Service, using the unsubscribe link within each email newsletter, or by contacting us as provided below to have your contact information removed from our promotional email list or registration database. These opt-out options do not apply to emails sent as fulfillment of our Products, as described above, as a result of a product purchase or product service experience, or other transactions initiated by you in relation to the Service.

 **Tracking Technologies (Cookies) and Advertising.** See section above on Cookies to learn how you can disable cookies via your web browser settings. Some browsers have incorporated

 **Advertising.** We may partner with third party ad networks to either display advertising on our Sites and/or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partners may use cookies and Web beacons to collect Navigational Data about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you want to not have this information used to serve you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: <http://preferences.truste.com/> (in the European Union, you can click here: <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising in general, and you may continue to receive generic ads. Additionally, you may be able to opt out of receiving personalized advertisements from other companies who are members of the Network Advertising Initiative or who subscribe to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. For more information about this practice and to understand your options, please visit: [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/), <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/> and [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

Promotional Offers from the ProjectManager. We offer a weekly newsletter where we advertise our Products and Products, along with other general resource content to help you manage your projects. On occasion, we partner with third party vendors to promote their goods and Products to you. To opt out of these offers, you can unsubscribe from the newsletter by clicking the “Unsubscribe” button at the bottom of the email newsletter. You can also email us at [support@projectmanager.com](mailto:support@projectmanager.com) or [tips@projectmanager.com](mailto:tips@projectmanager.com) or [legal@projectmanager.com](mailto:legal@projectmanager.com) to be removed.

 **Data portability.** There are a number of contexts with the Product where you have the ability to obtain your data in a portable format (such as exporting timesheets or resources or projects), and in some instances, you may request electronic files of select data (such as your basic account information.)

## How we transfer information we collect internationally

### International transfers of information we collect

We take steps to protect your information, whenever we transfer it. For the purpose of providing you our Products, we collect information globally and primarily store that information in the United States. Additionally, we transfer, process and store your information outside of your country of residence, to wherever we or our third-party service providers operate.

 **International transfers within ProjectManager Companies:** In order to facilitate our global Products operations, we transfer information to the United States and allow access to that information from countries in which ProjectManager and other ProjectManager affiliates have operations for the purposes described in this policy. Not all countries have equivalent privacy and data protection law. We make use of standard contractual data protection clauses whenever we share information about you within and among ProjectManager corporate affiliates, which have been approved by the European Commission, and we rely on the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework to safeguard the transfer of information we collect from the European Economic Area and Switzerland. Please see our Privacy Shield notice below for more information or contact us as provided below.

 **International transfers to third parties:** Regarding third parties described in this privacy policy, which provide Products to us under contract, many are based in other countries that may not have the same privacy and data protection laws as the country in which you reside. When we share information of customers in the European Economic Area or Switzerland, we make use of the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks, European Commission-approved standard contractual data protection clauses, binding corporate rules for transfers to data processors, or other appropriate legal mechanisms to safeguard the transfer. Please see our Privacy Shield Notice below.

## Other important privacy information

### Notice to End Users

Our Products are intended both for personal and organizational use. Where Products are made accessible to you via an organization (such as your employer), that organization acts as the administrator of our Products and is as such responsible for the end-users and/or Products that it controls. We are not responsible for the security or privacy practices or policies of an administrator or their organization, which may differ from this policy. As your use of our Products is subject to your organization’s policies, if applicable, please refer any of your data privacy questions to your account administrator.

It’s important to know that even when these Products are not presently administered to you by an organization, if you use a business email that is provided by an organization or are are part of a team administered by an organization and you access our Products, then the team administrator or the domain owner associated with your organization’s email address (e.g. your employer) may assert administrative control over your account and use of our Products at a later date, depending on the organization’s policies. You should inquire with your Administrator to understand whether you will be notified when this happens.

Project, team and list owners, as well as account administrators, have the ability to restrict your access to and access permissions within the respective project, team, list, board or account that the owner or administrator controls. In certain cases, your account administrators can also:

  * Access, control, update or delete your account information;
  * Change your account information, such as adding contact or profile information or changing the email address associated with your account;
  * Change or require you to reset your account password;
  * Restrict, suspend or terminate your access to our Products or your account;
  * Access or retain information stored as part of your account; and
  * Enable or disable third-party apps or integrations.

Please contact your account administrator or refer to your organization’s policies for more information.

## Our policy towards children

ProjectManager Products are not directed to individuals under the age of 16, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we are made aware that a child under the age of 16 has provided us with personal information, we will take immediate action to delete such information. If you are aware that a child under the age of 16 has provided us with personal information, please contact us immediately as directed below, so that we can investigate the matter and take immediate action.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by adding a notice on our Products homepages, login screens, or by sending you an email notification. We will also keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use our Products to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using our Products and deactivate your account(s), as outlined above.

## Contact Us

Your information is held by ProjectManager, Inc. If you have questions or concerns about how your information is handled, please contact us as follows:

ProjectManager.com, Inc.  
3420 Executive Center Drive, Suite 160  
Austin, TX 78731  
E-Mail: [legal@projectmanager.com](mailto:legal@projectmanager.com)

Last Modified: May 22, 2018
